Guide to the Roy Lisker Papers, 1957 -
Roy Lisker Papers 1957 -
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Roy Lisker
2001-68
42
100
Papers of mathematician, novelist, musician, publisher, and social critic Roy Lisker. Lisker publishes Ferment magazine and is the proprietor of the Ferment Press.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisitions Information
Acquired from Roy Lisker, 2001. Additional donations periodically given by Roy Lisker.
Collection Overview
Papers of mathematician, novelist, musician, publisher, and social critic Roy Lisker. Lisker publishes Ferment magazine and is the proprietor of the Ferment Press.
Collection Arrangement
Lisker transfers papers in archival cartons, which have been rehoused in archival document boxes. The original order of the materials has been maintained, and is noted by the "Old box" series headings. The archival document box holdings are noted in the scope and content notes for the "Old box" series (for example, "Old box 26: Journals" will be found in archival boxes 49-50).
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Old box 1: Journals,1989-1999
  - April,1989 (Box 1)
  - Pianowandeljahre Notebook,May 1994-July 1995 (Box 1)
  - Lectures, Concerts, Seminars in Boston,February 1993-June 1994 (Box 1)
  - Middletown Journal, Background research on Yugoslavia, Eastern Europe, etc.,December 1994 (Box 1)
  - Boston Notebooks,September 1993-June 1994 loose pages in envelope (Box 1)
  - Lyric Journal ,August 1995 (Box 1)
  - Winter Journal,October 29, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Planning Notebook,March 24, 1996; April 21, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Journal,March 27, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Notebook,June 1996 (Box 2)
  - Middletown Journal,November 1997 (Box 2)
  - Berkeley Notebook,April 14, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Artist's Pad: Boulder Novelist Conference,September 1992 (Box 3)
  - Memoir, Draft Version,May 1997 (Box 3)
  - Studies,August 1997 (Box 3)
  - Projects,January 1997 (Box 3)
  - Journal,March, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Schedules,November 1999 (Box 3)
  - Journal,September 29, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Notebook,July 1996 (Box 3)
- Old box 2: Scientific Journals,1988-2000
  - January, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Math Notebook,November 1997 (Box 4)
  - Math Notebook,April 1997 (Box 4)
  - October 30, 19881988 (Box 4)
  - Quantum Theory Investigations, January 1992 (Box 4)
  - Mathematics,September 1996 (Box 4)
  - Computation Notebook,March 24, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Quantum Revision,May 24, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Computation Notebook,March 2000 (Box 4)
  - Science Studies, August 1999 (Box 5)
  - December 22, 19981998 (Box 5)
  - November 13, 1998,1998 (Box 5)
  - October 13, 1998,1998 (Box 5)
  - May 14, 1998, 1998 (Box 5)
  - January,1999 (Box 5)
  - March, 1999 (Box 5)
  - December,1999 (Box 5)
  - Notebook loose pages,September 26, 1997 (Box 5)
- Old box 3: Ferment/New Universe Weekly,1980-1983
  - New Universe Weekly. Volume I, January - December, 1980 (Box 6)
  - New Universe Weekly, Vol. I. Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - New Universe Weekly, Vol. II, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - New Universe Weekly, Vols. III - V, 1982-1983 (Box ?)
  - New Universe Weekly. Selection of Science Articles (Box 6)
  - Ferment: Volumes I, II, III (Box 6)
  - Ferment IV, Small Format (Box ?, Folder ?)
  - Ferment V: Issues 9 to 14 (Box 7)
  - Ferment V I: Large Format, Issues 2,3,5 and part of 7 (Box 7)
- Old box 4: Journals1997-2000
  - Schedules Notebook,January 1998 (Box 7)
  - April 28, 1998 (Box 7)
  - June 6, 1998 (Box 7)
  - July 29, 1998 (Box 7)
  - October 15, 1998 (Box 7)
  - July,1999 (Box 8)
  - October, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Studies, July 1997 (Box 8)
  - Winter, 2000 (Box 8)
  - March 17, 2000 (Box 8)
  - August, 2000 (Box 8)
  - Journal, May 16, 2000 (Box 9)
- Old box 5: Music1963-1987
  - Nirvana (Box 9)
    (i) Concert Song, Soprano. Voice and Piano 1966
    (ii) Photocopy of Soprano
    (iii)Photocopy of Alto Arrangement
    (iv) Alto, Expanded Version
  - Nirvana, Original Handwritten Scorem Pen and Ink (Box 9)
    (i) Soprano
    (ii) Alto (Page 3 Missing)
    (iii)Vocal Score, Soprano (Page 3 missing)
  - Through My Window, Original Handwritten Score, Pen and Ink Voice and Piano 1972 (Box 9)
  - Sketches for Song on Derry Massacre, 1971 (Box 9)
  - "Treize Etudes Pour Guitare" 1970, published Edutions Max Eschig, 1972 (Box 9)
    (i) Copy of Max Eschig original
    (ii) Photocopy
  - Associative Harmony, Essay in Music Theory (Box 9)
    (i) Version of 1963
    (ii) Version of 1987
  - Baroque Sonata, Flute (Recorder) and Harpsichord (Box 9)
    Original handwritten score. Page 33 missing, replaces with photocopy
  - 3 Pieces for Flute and Violin (Box 9)
    (i)Ferment Press score, bound
    (ii)Original handwritten score
  - 7 Love Songs, Low Voice and Guitar. Photocopy,1987 (Box 9)
  - Music Publicity, Ferment Press.1983-1987 (Box 9)
  - 7 Love Songs. (Box 9)
    Original Camera Copy version
  - Volume II of Folk Songs in Classical Arrangements,1987 (Box 9)
  - Vol. 1. Folk Songs in Classical Arrangements, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Variations for Guitar "Ma Belle Si Tu Voulais" (Box 9)
    (i)Original version, pen and ink (final page missing)
    (ii) felt pen version, complete
    (iii) Pasteup for photocopy, complete
    (iv) ferment Press photocopy
  - Sketches for Songs. Lower East Side, Winter 1966 (Box 9)
    (i) Bhagavad Gita 8:18
    (ii) Pomes Pennyeach of James Joyce
    (iii) Haiku's
  - Sketches for Piano Pieces (Box 10)
    (i)Arabesque: Brussels, Belgium, 1970
    (ii)Sonata movement, New York 1966
    (iii) Two-Tone music: Philadelphia 1967
  - Manuscript Book, 1970-1976 (Box 10)
    Dublin, Paris, New York
  - Compositions, Studies and Sketches; Philadelphia-NYC,1964-1967 (Box 10)
  - Folk-Songs, original manuscripts (Box 10)
    List on torn cover of 39 songs
    Original Song: Lullaby
    2 voice arrangement
    Original Song: Jacqueline
    Original Song: Summer
    "Ma Belle, Si Tu Voulais"-Pencil
    "Last Rose of Summer" Pen and Ink
    "Lusty Young Smith"
    "John Henry"
    "Cherry Tree Carol"- Pencil
    "Silent Night" -Pencil
    "The Lover's Ghost" - Felt Pen
    " The Maid of Newfoundland"--Felt Pen
    Lullaby - chords only
    "Muwashshah" on reverse side
    Guitar, no words
    "Moreton Bay"
    "Go Down, Moses"
    "House of the Rising Sun" Pencil
    "Drover's Dream" Pencil
    "Waltzing Mathilda" Pencil
    "Moreton Bay" Pen
    "Streets of Forbes" Pen
    "Die Lorelei" Pencil
    "Muwashshah" Pen; with words
    "Oft in the Stilly Night" Pencil
    "The Willow Song" - Pencil
    "Waltzing Mathilda"; Pencil
    "Papillon, tu est voyage" Sketch only, pencil
    "The New Jerusalem"
    ' The Cutty Wren" Pen and Pencil
    " Sixteen Tons" Notes only
    Original song: Elsinore Pencil
    "Le Deserteur" Pencil
    "Peat Bog Soldiers" Pencil
    "Bold Fenian Men" Pen and Pencil
    " Down By the Sally Gardens"; Pen and Pencil
    "Las Tres Hoyas"
    "Papillon, Tu es Voyage"; Arrangement in Pencil; Melody line in red ink
    "Du Maydele Du Fayns" Pen, Ballpoint
    "Scottish Lullaby ' Original words Pen
    "The Broomfield Hill" Ballpoint
    "All My Trials"
    "Ye Mariners All" Pencil
    "Down By the Sally Gardens" Pen
    "Los Cuatro Muleros" Pencil
    "Greensleeves" Pencil
    "The Evening Winds", Pen Original Words
    "Blue Moon" Pen
    "Cocaine Blues" Pencil Chords
    "The Three Fishers" Felt Pen
    "Ma Belle, Si Tu Voulais" Felt Pen
    "Waltzing Mathilda" Felt Pen
    "Aunt Rhody" Felt Pen
    "Los Reyes de la Baraja" Felt Pen
    "The Unquiet Grave" Felt Pen
    " The Lover's Ghost" Felt Pen
    " Le Deserteur" Felt Pen
    "The Lusty Young Smith" Felt Pen
    "Franky and Johnny" Felt Pen
    " Henry Martin" Felt Pen
    "Edward" -Felt Pen
    "Streets of Forbes" - Felt Pen
    "The Peat-Bog Soldiers"
    "Barbara Allen"
    "The House of the Rising Sun"
    "Ye Mariners All"
    " Du Maydele Du Feyns"
    "Ma Belle si Tu Voulais"-Ballpoint Pen
    "Die Lorelei" -Pencil
    "Jacqueline" - Ballpoint
    "Summer" Ballpoint
    " Spring Song" Ball point
    "Lullaby" chords. Ballpoint
    "Unquiet Grave" Felt Pen
    "Go Down, Moses" -Pen
    " The Lover's Ghost" Pen
    "Les Trois Petits Enfants" Pen
    "Les Trois Petits Enfants" -Pencil
    "Scottish Lullaby" Pen
    "Les Trois Petits Enfants" Pencil
    "Oy Azoy Neyt A Shnayder" Pencil
    "Franky and Johnny" 4 Versions
    "Barbara Allen" Felt Pen, words on back
    "Barbara Allen" Felt Pen
    "Du Maydele du Fayns" Pencil
    "Hava Naghila" Pen
    "Down By The Sally Gardens" Pencil
    "Nobody Knows The Trouble I've Seen" - 2 pencil versions
    "Which Side Are You On?" 3 Versions
    "Nobody Knows The Trouble I've Seen" - Pen
    "Three Fishers" Pencil Sketch
    "All My Trials" Pencil Sketch
    "Unquiet Grave" Pencil
    "Hier Apres-midi" Original; satire on student restaurants in Paris.
    "Down By the Sally Gardens" 2 Voice version, Pen
    "Barbara Allen" Ink and Pencil
    "All My Trials" Pencil
    "Three Fishers" Sketch
    "Three Fishers", complete. Pencil
    "Henry Martin" Pencil
    "Maid of Newfoundland" Felt Pen
    'Maid of Newfoundland' Pencil
    "Muwashshah" Pencil Sketch
    "Franky and Johnny" Pencil
    "Go Down, Moses" Pencil
    "Greensleeves" Pen
    "Ye Mariners All" -Pen
    "House of the Rising Sun" Pen
    "Bulbas" Pen
    "Chalita" Tango; Pencil
    "Les Trois Petits Enfants" Felt Pen
    "Los Reyes de la Baraca" Pencil
    "Henry Martin" Felt Pen
    "Evening Winds" Pencil
- Old box 6: Documents, Theater and Manuscripts1968-1991
  Bard College Documents
  - Envelope I (Box 11)
  - Envelope II (Box 11)
  - Envelope III (Box 11)
  - News Clippings (Box 11)
  - Draft Card Burning: Articles, Papers (Box 11)
  - News Clippings (Box 11)
  - Children's Play "The Kangaroo That Wanted To Sing" (Box 11)
  - 3 scripts with related materials from the Poughkeepsie production, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Chronology of Years in Europe in 49 chapters1968-1972 (Box 12)
  - Playscript "Rehabilitation", 1976-1980 (Box 12)
    two copies
  - Film Script "Commerce and Illusions,"1969 (Box 12)
    two copies, final page of the outline is missing
  - Play "Hamlet's Psychiatrist,"version of 1976 (Box 12)
  - Film script "Unto The Third Generation" (Box 12)
    2 copies
  - Photocopy of the text of French Translation of Meal Ticket Editions Rene Julliard, 1972 (Box 12)
- Old box 7: Notebooks1979-1997
  - January, 1979 (Box ?, Folder ?)
  - October, 1977 (Box ?, Folder ?)
  - June, 1995 (Box 13)
  - May, 1995 (Box 13)
    two directions
  - Causation and Epistemology, March 2, 1993 (Box 13)
  - "Greater Middletown Cultural Region," August 26, 1996 (Box 13)
  - January, 1995 (Box 13)
  - July, 1995 (Box 13)
  - September, 1995 (Box 13)
  - September, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Fermat Conference, Boston University, July 23, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Piano Wandeljahre Notebook, October 11, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Berkeley, March 3, 1992 (Box 14)
  - February, 1994 (Box 14)
  - March 13, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Berkeley, January 22, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Berkeley, Seminars, Lectures, January 24, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Berkeley, December 27, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Planning, Middletown July 11, 1995 (Box ?, Folder ?)
  - September 10, 1991 (Box 15)
  - December, 1995 (Box 15)
  - December 3, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Woods Hole, August, 1993 (Box 15)
  - September 9, 1995 (Box 15)
  - October 23, 1993 (Box 15)
    Small format
- Old box 8: Math and Science Journals1977-1995
  - Fractals and Chaos April 5, 1994 (Box 16)
  - Colorado, December 4, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Study of Probability and Statistics, September 1995 (Box 16)
  - January 15, 1994 (Box 16)
  - Dynamical Systems Paper, February 22, 1995 (Box 16)
  - November 1985 (Box 16)
  - August 1985 (Box 16)
  - Santa Cruz, February 23, 1984 (Box 16)
  - September 1982 (Box 17)
  - Hudson Valley July 1979 (Box 17)
  - April 1979 (Box 17)
  - September 1983 (Box 17)
  - November 1984 (Box 17)
  - January 1989 (Box 17)
  - October 1977 (Box 17)
  - June 1, 1989 (Box 17)
  - August 26/September 14, 1987 (Box 18)
    bidirectional
  - December 1, 1986 (Box 18)
  - August 1988 (Box 18)
  - Math Notebook, March 6, 1994 (Box 18)
- Old box 9: Journals1977-1987
  - october 1977 (Box 18)
  - January 1979 (Box 18)
  - June 1979 (Box 18)
  - May 1980 (Box 19)
  - December 1980 (Box 19)
  - January 1982 (Box 19)
  - March 1982 (Box 19)
  - April 1982 (Box 19)
  - Descriptions Journal 1983 (Box 19)
  - January 1984 (Box 19)
  - May 1986 (Box 20)
  - October 1987 (Box 20)
  - March 1987 (Box 20)
  - Hamlet Essay (Box 20)
- Old box 10: Journals, General1987-1994
  - March 26, 1991 (Box Oversize)
  - March 30, 1992 (Box Oversize)
  - February 19, 1990 (Box Oversize)
  - May 1994 (Box 20)
  - April 1988 (Box 20)
  - January 14, 1989 (Box 20)
  - April 1989 (Box 20)
  - Paris Itinerary, February 1988 (Box 21)
  - December 1987 (Box 21)
  - Europe, February 1989 (Box 21)
  - General October 22, 1993 (Box 21)
  - Poetic October 22, 1993 (Box 21)
  - January 26, 1993 (Box 22)
  - November 1990 (Box 22)
  - May 1990 (Box 22)
  - Denver, June 1993 (Box 22)
  - September 1993 (Box 22)
  - February 1991 (Box 22)
  - July 1993 (Box 22)
  - General,1989 (Box 22)
- Old box 11: Journals, General1964-1993
  - Notebook of Descriptions, October 22, 1993 (Box 23)
  - Boughton Place Translation Project; Mathematics, September 8, 1993 (Box 23)
  - October 14, 1992 (Box 23)
  - January 26, 1992 (Box 23)
  - France/Catalog Boughton Place 1989, 1991 (Box 23)
  - December 1992 (Box 23)
  - Lyric Journal October 1991 (Box 24)
  - January 1990 (Box 24)
  - Donation Cards July 1993 (Box 24)
  - April 17, 1991 (Box 24)
  - July 1987 (Box 24)
  - October 22, 1991 (Box 24)
  - March 1985 (Box 24)
  - April 1988 (Box 24)
  - Livres de Brouillon, November 13, 1988 (Box 24)
  - Cambridge, Mass. December, 1964 (Box 24)
  - CBC Program Chilean Refugees, November 1973 (Box 24)
  - Racism Seminar-La Legua, 1974 (Box 24)
- Old box 12: Mathematics Notebooks1979-1996
  - Applied Abstract Algebra,January 21, 1991 (Box 25)
  - Computation Notebook,October 1994 (Box 25)
  - Dynamical Systems, December 1994 (Box 25)
  - December 20, 1989 (Box 25)
  - August 5, 1985 (Box 25)
  - August 9, 1984 (Box 25)
  - Dynamical Systems, September 18, 1994 (Box 25)
  - January 3, 1987 (Box 25)
  - March 1988 (Box 26)
  - November 1979 (Box 26)
  - September 26, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Dynamical Systems, October 1994 (Box 26)
  - Dynamical Systems, December 13, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Bryn Mawr Programme/Ecology House Wesleyan, April 1982 (Box 26)
  - Chandrasekhar Conference, December 14-15, 1996 (Box 26)
  - July 1991 (Box 26)
  - September 1983 (Box ?)
  - Dynamical Systems, September 1994 (Box 26)
  - June 1994 (Box 27)
  - April 19, 1996 (Box 27)
  - October 23, 1993 (Box 27)
  - August 12, 1994 (Box 27)
  - July 21, 1993 (Box 27)
  - March 5, 1991 (Box 27)
  - March 9, 1991 (Box 27)
  - December 5, 1996 (Box 27)
  - September 1993 (Box 27)
- Old box 13: Journals, Notebooks1977-2001
  - Polyforms, July 11, 1990 (Box 28)
  - July 3, 1991 (Box 28)
  - Science Notebook, September 26, 1991 (Box 28)
  - Lyric Journal, December 16, 2001 (Box 28)
  - Mathematics, February 20, 1992 (Box 28)
  - Quantum Theory, Aprul 27, 1992 (Box 28)
  - June 18, 1992 (Box 28)
  - Mathematics, June 24, 1992 (Box 28)
  - Mathematics, October 14, 1992 (Box 29)
  - Computation Book, March 27, 1980 (Box 29)
  - Mathematics, January 14, 1993 (Box 29)
  - Denver Journal, March 15, 1993 (Box 29)
  - April 29, 1993 (Box 29)
  - February 14, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Pianowandeljahre, June 1994 (Box 29)
  - October 1994 (Box 30)
  - Ferment Accounts, September 29, 1993 (Box 30)
  - July 22, 1998 (Box 30)
  - Tivoli, NY, January 1977 (Box 30)
- Old box 14: Novels1970-2001
  - El Pessebre (Box 30-31)
    Puerto Rico, Summer 1982
    Puerto Rico: Materials for "Puerto Rico, Culture, Tourism and Politics" June 1982
    YMHA Composers Conference, February 7, 1981
    MSS of "El Pessebre" 150 pages
    Background notes for "El Pessebre"
  - Chronicles of Nin (Box 32)
    "Chronicles of Nin" 1970 Version
    "Chronicles of Nin" Revision of 2001, loose pages
  - harvest of Chains (Box 32)
    Harvest of Chains, Original Typescript 1970
    Sampling of Chapters, 1989
    Revision of 1989, typescript
  - Getting that Meal Ticket (Box 32)
    Meal Ticket: Original Typescript, Paris 1972
  - Micellaneous (Box 32)
    Berkeley Love Story, Originals
- Old box 15: 1968-1991
  - causal Algebras Berkeley, reduced format, 1983-1987 (Box 32)
  - Typescript, Einstein Centennial Symposium Article. Berkeley Version, 1986 (Box 32)
  - Novel, 'The Eiffel Tower Gang", complete, Ferment Version, 1990-1991 (Box 32)
  - Hamlet Essay, "The Corpse in the Bedroom," Large and Small formats (Box 33)
  - "Street Musician in France" - Play fragment (Box 33)
  - Catalogues, Fall 1989 (Box 33)
  - Ferment Press Catalogue, 1991 (Box 33)
  - Film Script "The Feedback Box," 1972 (Box 33)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, Misc, 1973-1974 (Box 33)
  - Essay, "Ainay Le Chateau", with ideas for a film script, 1968 (Box 33)
  - Copy of French Variety Magazine " Journal du Show Business", 1970 (Box 34)
  - Europe. Loose Journal Pages, 1988 (Box 34)
  - Two articles, photocopies, from "Les Temps Modernes" (Box 34)
    Une Gauche Embryonaire
    In Memoriam Einstein
  - Typescript of Ferment Press book: "Shrinking Expectations" (Box 34)
- Old box 16: Short Stories, etc.1957-1995
  - Short Story, " The Invalid", Philadelphia, 1957 (Box 34)
  - "After The Funeral " Paris, 1969 (Box 34)
  - "Hallucinations" Paris, 1969 (Box 34)
  - "Chuang-Tzu and the Butterfly" MacDowell Colony, 1962 (Box 34)
  - "Anaesthesia"; Cologne Journal; Landreville Journal, France 1969-72 (Box 34)
  - Journal Transcriptions: Philadelphia 1961, Boston 1964, Montreal 1968, France 1969 (Box 34)
  - "Street Musician in France" English version of article published in Les Temps Modernes, 1970 (Box 34)
  - Essays 1967-1969 (Box 34)
    Lecture Notes "French Anti-Novel" delivered at the Ethical Culture Society, Philadelphia, 1967
    "Free University in the Modern World" 1968
    "The Underground Newspaper in America" 1968
    2 articles published in BUNAC (British Universities North American Club ),1968,69
  - "Dedication" ( 2 copies) (Box 34)
  - "Temple of Music" ( Carbon copy) Paris, 1969 (Box 34)
  - "Fantasy and Science Fiction." Original Version of "Sea Urchins", Philadelphia, 1958 (Box 34)
  - "Shrinking Expectations" MSS. and Source Materials, 1967 (Box 34)
  - "Shrinking Expectations" Book II. Source Materials and sketches (Box 34)
  - "Time and the Maya" Version of 1986 (Box 35)
  - "Einstein Centennial Symposium" Ferment Press Version Typescript, 1987 (Box 35)
  - New Universe Weekly, Volume I. Originals (Box 35)
  - Applied Abstract Algebra, Book Project, 1991 (Box 35)
  - "Question Theory" research notebooks, 1993 (Box 35)
  - Ferment Press Catalogue, 1994. Large and Small Format; Teaching Resume 1995; Math Consultant to the Arts; Inventory of Scientific Articles Version of 4/9/95 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Journalism, 1969-1972 (Box 35)
  - MacDowell Colony short narrative experiments, 1962 (Box 35)
- Old box 17: 1959-1996
  - "Causal Algebras" Commentary and Outline (Box 35)
  - Documents of Boughton Place dispute,January 1992 (Box 35)
  - Ellis Horwood Correspondence,1988-90 (Box 36)
  - Various letters,1987-1995 (Box 36)
  - List of 45 ideas for research projects,March 1990 (Box 36)
  - Writings in psychology. Pre-revision versions,1986-1990 (Box 36)
  - "Hysteria and Enlightenment" Mesmer/Marie-Therese von Paradis Ferment VII, complete (Box 36)
  - "Grothendieck" articles. Background materials (Box 36)
  - "Revolution at Pierrefonds" original English version of Temps Modernes article, 1969 ( page 18 missing) (Box 36)
  - Support letters sent to Gale Publications,1996 (Box 36)
  - Cambridge/Philadelphia Journal,1959-1960 (Box 36)
  - "Memoir" Draft Typescript (Box 37)
  - Account of a hitch-hiking journey, Montreal-East Chicago,1973 (Box 37)
  - Source materials, "John Nash" articles (Box 37)
  - Philadelphia in the 60's: Sketches and Ferment article (Box 37)
  - Montreal,( Report on Housing violations),1974 (Box 37)
  - Hungary, Materials,Summer 1999 (Box 37)
  - Sketches for a Novel, Berkley,1986 (Box 37)
  - Paris Stories,1969 (Box 37)
  - "Novel of the Americas" Political Action of CU Boulder Campus,September 1992 (Box 37)
- Old box 18: Ferment Originals, Large1988
  - Ferment XIII (Box 38)
  - Ferment XII (Box 38)
  - Ferment XI (Box 38)
  - Ferment X (Box 38)
  - Ferment IX. Notebooks from France, 1988 (Box 39)
  - Ferment IX#9: Quantum article, with notes (Box 39)
  - Ferment IX (Box 39)
  - Ferment VIII (Box 39)
- Old box 19: Poetry1958-2001
  - Stupid Songs, Original (Box 39)
  - The Deluge MacDowell Colony, 1962 (Box 39)
  - Lyric Journal, miscellaneous pages, 1992 (Box 39)
  - "Lightning Crashes Around Thunder-Echoing Skies" Version of October, 2000 (Box 39)
  - Clearwater Revival booklet, June 1988 (Box 39)
  - Clearwater, Source Materials (Box 39)
  - Monologues: (Box 39)
    Gerard Debreu's Nobel Prize Award: Proving Reaganomics by Pure Mathematics
    Tale of the Guru
  - Chants and Sound Poetry (Box 39)
    i. Autumn Chant
    ii. Was the Dog Walking the Dog
    iii. That Bad Bat
    iv. Junk Truck, version of October 1984
    v. Dinosaur Chant, version of August 1984
    vi. Lethal Evil Level
    vii. Battle Ax Battle
    viii. Warble Chant
    viii. When Oxen Knock Sick Clocks
    ix. Uranium
    x. Megatherium
    xi. Rainbow Gathering Chant
    xii. Memory
    xiii. Murmur
    xiv. Wash
    xv. Atavism
  - "Kaleidoscope" (Box 39)
  - Early Poetry, 1958-1960 (Box 40)
  - Emerald Flames (Box 40)
  - Hamlet Essay Version of 1990 (Box 40)
  - Philadelphia Intelligencer Vol. I# (Box 40)
  - Pages, Lyric Anthology, 1992 (Box 40)
  - "Transformation" for Patricia Spencer and Diane Macintosh, 1980-1981 (Box 40)
  - 11 Matrix Poems, 1981 (Box 40)
    Lightnings Crash, Version of 1985
  - Paris Sketches, 1968 (Box 40)
  - Play " MIT Information Desk," 1964 (Box 40)
  - The Deluge Typescript 1962 (Box 40)
  - The Deluge, Revision pages, 2001 (Box 40)
  - "Barbarians in the Salon" Originals, 1986 and Lawrence Wechsler correspondence 1991 (Box 40)
  - "Requiem for a Dead SAAB," 1979 (Box 40)
  - Play "Dr. Phillipe Pinel," 1964 (Box 40)
  - Collection of Posters, 1994-2001 (Box 40)
- Old box 20: Complete File Ferment Press Books1986-2000
  - Tales of Frustrated Musicians (Box 41)
  - Governments of Chelm (Box 41)
  - Persephone (Box 41)
  - Cynical Xmas Stories (Box 41)
  - Four Nature Myths (Box 41)
  - Cats and Crazy Razors (Box 41)
  - Quest of the Absolute (Box 41)
  - Vagabond Violin (Box 41)
  - Sea Urchins (Box 41)
  - Urban Tendrils: (Box 41)
    The Drugstore
    Logan Airport
  - Puerto Rico, Music, Tourism and Politics (Box 41)
  - Bach, Handel, Mozart (Box 41)
  - Corpse in the Bedroom (Box 41)
  - Barbarians in the Salon (Box 41)
  - Life and Life Energy (Box 41)
  - Love and Cosmology (Box 41)
  - Shrinking Expectations (Box 41)
  - Question Theory (Box 41)
  - Malevolent Malpractice (Box 41)
  - Projective Constructs (Box 41)
  - Non-Linear Algebra and Dynamical Systems (Box 41)
  - Iterate Sequence (Box 41)
  - Circular Tangrams (Box 41)
  - Weakly Infinite Cardinals (Box 41)
  - Causal Algebras (Box 41)
  - Barrier Theory (Box 41)
  - Euclidean Geometry, Time and Relativity (Box 41)
  - Alexander Yesenin-Volpin (Box 41)
  - Quest for Grothendieck ( 3 volumes) (Box 41)
  - Fermat's Last Theorem (Box 41)
  - Pons Asinorum (Box 41)
  - Benoit Mandelbrot/ Ignatius Y. Snew (Box 41)
  - Chomsky's Linguistics Exposed! (Box 41)
  - Introduction to Quantum Theory for the General Public (Box 41)
  - In Memoriam Einstein (Box 42)
  - Emerald Flames (Box 42)
  - Lyric Anthology I (Box 42)
  - Kaleidoscope (Box 42)
  - Chants and Monologues (Box 42)
  - 3 Rousing Chants (Box 42)
  - Drum Songs (Box 42)
  - Clearwater Revival (Box 42)